Guide to the Audrey Tompkins Summers Scrapbook
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Audrey Tompkins Summers scrapbook
1942-1947
SC0543
Summers, Audrey Tompkins.
1 Linear feet
This scrapbook was kept by Audrey Tompkins during her high school and college years. It contains programs, dance cards, menus, tickets, notices, and other memorabilia, largely documenting her social life, with a few items pertinent to her academic life at Stanford. There are also a few objects such as a spoon, a spent flash bulb, and hair clippings.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Purchased, 1998.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Audrey Tompkins earned her A.B. in psychology at Stanford University in 1947. She married James Leonard Summers, a member of the Stanford Class of 1946.
Description of the Collection
This scrapbook was kept by Audrey Tompkins during her high school and college years. It contains programs, dance cards, menus, tickets, notices, and other memorabilia, largely documenting her social life, with a few items pertinent to her academic life at Stanford. There are also a few objects such as a spoon, a spent flash bulb, and hair clippings.
Access Terms
Summers, Audrey Tompkins.; Scrapbooks; Women --California --Social life and customs.; Young women --California.
Collection Contents
- Papers, 1942-1947
  - Page 1 and 2, 1943 September 16-23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Mountain View High School memorabilia; photo of high school students at Earl Carroll Theatre Restaurant in Hollywood; RR schedule to Los Angeles; Key Magazine (events in southern California)
  - Page 3 and 4, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Booklet "Memories of My Senior Year," including photos; her high school commencement programl S.U. commencement program
  - Page 5, 1944 Summer and September (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Memorabilia from dates with Arne; program from "Goodnight Ladies," S.F. theater
  - Page 6, Circa 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Spoon from Palo Alto Hospital; instructions for card tricks at California-USC game
  - Page 7 and 8, 1944 November 18-23 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Football program USC v. California; A.S.T.P. Thanksgiving Dinner menu; brochure "Stanford Songs and Yells" published through courtesy of Hotel St. Francis; drinking straws from Wilsons and the Stanford Union; program and ticket stubs from Gaieties
  - Page 9 and 10, 1944 Fall and Winter (Box 1, Folder 6)
    S.U. registration certificate; dance memorabilia; Christmas and New Year's memorabilia; spent flash bulb from photo taken at dance club
  - Page 11 and 12, 1945 January-March (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Memorabilia from various social events; social events with Jimmy Summers; her birthday; winter quarter registration card
  - Page 13, 1945 March-April (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Point Lobos brochure; various social events
  - Page 14, 1944 November-1945 Spring (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Dance card; pressed flowers from bouquet from Jimmy; tickets from Stanford dances
  - Page 15 and 16, 1945 February-April (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Notices to appear before Committee of Five for being out after hours ("technical lockout"); card for dance at Roble Gym; matches and napkins from various dinners and dances
  - Page 17 and 18, 1945 Summer (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Matches and napkins from various dinners and dances
  - Page 19, 1945 December-1946 January (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Pressed flowers; memorabilia from dinners and dances
  - Page 20 and 21, 1945 December-1946 November (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Sketch of Jimmy; cards re Red and White Ball and Lagunita Formal Dance; Hotel Claremont memorabilia; drink menu from Trader Sam's
  - Page 22, 1946 February-March (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Social events
  - Clippings and newspapers, Circa 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbook covers, circa 1942-1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Page 23, 1945 November-1946 April (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Dance and theater memorabilia
  - Page 24, 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Gaieties program; Mission Ranch brochure; Restaurant reservation card; dance memorabilia
  - Page 25, circa 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Libretto from Il Trovatore
  - Page 26, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Coasters and napkins from restaurants; clipping of a cartoon
  - Page 27, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Ram's Head program; basketball program; Orchesis program
  - Page 28, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Stanford dance cards
  - Page 28, circa 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Instructions for selling ads in Chaparral
  - Page 29, circa 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Cartoon; Ram's Head program
  - Dance cards and miscellany, circa 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Pressed flowers from page 23, circa 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Hair clippings, circa 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Sugar cube, circa 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 12)